A Guide to the Virginia Hisey Myers Collection, 1894-1900
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Virginia Hisey Myers Collection 1894-1900
Special Collections, James Madison University
2068
This collection consists of 10 business ledgers in two Hollinger boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Virginia Hisey Myers, through Mr. Douglas Dellinger, in November 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
This collection consists of ten business ledgers from L. M Hisey & Co. and Wightman & Hisey, 1894-1900. These businesses, located in Shenandoah County near Edinburgh, dealt in farm-related products and implements.
Scope and Content
The ledgers in this collection document sales of and orders for agricultural and forestry items, especially phosphate, coal, wheat, bark, and lumber, as well as corn and tools such as plows. Some ledgers also contain financial information about the companies, such as lists of notes due. Receipts and bills, inserted in a few of the ledgers, further document the businesses.
Arrangement
none
Contents List
- Box 1
  - Phosphate Book 1894
  - Phosphate Book 1895
  - Phosphate Book 1896
    These ledgers contain individual accounts, orders received, and other business dealings mostly concerning phosphate.
  - Coal Book 1894
    Individual accounts for lump and nut coal sold, including bushels, pounds, hauling, and price; and coal received.
  - Order Book 1898
    General ledger of miscellaneous accounts.
- Box 2
  - Invoice of Wightman and Hisey 1896
    List of accounts.
  - General Ledger of Accounts 1898-1899
  - General Ledger of Accounts 1899-1900
  - Wheat Book 1899-1900
    Wheat accounts of individuals.
  - Merchants and Farmers Bank [Book] 1897-1900
    General ledger of accounts.